Guide to the Edgar Hockley Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
Edgar Hockley collection
1886-1924
1886-1897
MSS.9
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
1.68
4 boxes
This collection comprises costume and set design drawings by Edgar Hockley depicting late-Victorian London stage productions. Also present are theatre programs and clippings from the same period.
Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
Cattermole, Charles, active 1859
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series: I. Theatre Programs and Clippings; II. Designs By Production; III. Designs By Era; IV. Designs By Subject. Folders are arranged alphabetically by production (Series I and II) or topic (Series III and IV).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired 2004, Paul Mellon Fund.
Biographical / Historical
The artist Edgar Hockley (1860-1938) achieved primary success as a wood-engraver, the profession listed alongside his name in the census of 1881. In 1891 he is listed as "wood engraver and draughtsman"; in 1901, as "retired wood engraver." The Victoria & Albert Museum notes: "Edgar Hockley's connections with the theatrical world and the specific reason for executing these sketches [in the V&A's collection of related material] is still unknown. Hockley was not designing anything, but recording finished productions and noting details of their appearance, especially their colours that he identified using professional paint colour names such as 'madder', 'gamboge' and 'cobalt blue'. From what we can glean of his life from census returns there is no evidence of theatrical relations or links, although he must have been well known especially in the London theatre world to gain entry to the dress rehearsals of the productions he sketched. It is highly unlikely that he could have made sketches and detailed notes such as these from a seat in a darkened auditorium." For the V&A's full description of Hockley, and their collection of Hockley material, see: http://www.vam.ac.uk/archives/unit/ARC16535
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of about 270 sheets containing approximately 1,000 costume and set design drawings by Edgar Hockley from late-Victorian London stage productions, many of which are believed to have been commissioned by Henry Irving. Also present are theatre programs and clippings from the same period. Drawings in the collection are unsigned; attribution to Hockley is based on a similar collection of drawings in the archives of the Victoria & Albert Museum. Hockley's name also appears on one envelope in the collection, box 4, item 10a.
A large majority of the drawings were made using graphite only, but a number also contain watercolor, pen and ink, and gouache. Most of the drawings are accompanied by detailed notes on colors or other aspects of appearance.
Bibliography
Bailey, Celia E. "The Cattermole Family of Artists Part Two: The Second Generation." The Magazine for the International Collector of Watercolours, Drawings and Prints, v. 6.1 (1991), p. 27-29.
Booth, Michael R. Theatre in the Victorian Age. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1991.
Holland, Peter. "The RSC and Studio Shakespeare." Essays in Criticism, v. 32.3 (July 1982), p. 205-218.
Irving, Henry, and Jeffrey Richards. Theatre, Culture and Society: Essays, Addresses and Lectures. Keele: Ryburn Publishing, Keele University Press, 1994.
Jowers, Sidney J, and John Cavanagh. Theatrical Costume, Masks, Make-Up and Wigs: A Bibliography and Iconography. London: Routledge, 2000.
Richards, Jeffrey. Sir Henry Irving: A Victorian Actor and His World. London: Hambledon and London, 2005.
Rowell, George. Theatre in the Age of Irving. Totowa, N.J: Rowman and Littlefield, 1981.
Stoker, Bram. Personal Reminiscences of Henry Irving. New York: Macmillan, 1906.
Costume design -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Costume designers -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Costume -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Theater -- Great Britain -- 19th century; Theaters -- Great Britain -- Stage-setting and scenery -- 19th century; Costume design drawings; Gouaches; Graphite drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Set design drawings; Theater programs; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 ( Stage history); Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1847-1928
- Theatre Programs & Clippings, 1886-1924; Series I
  - As You Like It: illustration of costume for Rosalind in Family Herald Supplement and another clipping, 1896, 1899; 2 clippings; 19.5 x 11 cm and 29 x 19.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 1a)
    Scope and Contents
    Two clippings from the Family Herald Supplement, one of which may have been included as proof of date of the other; however, close inspection provides the potential year of 1896 for the As You Like It illustration, which differs from the date on the other clipping.
    Wood engravings; Clippings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. As you like it; Neilson, Julia, b. 1868; Alexander, George, Sir, 1858-1918
  - Becket: program for the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1893 July; 4 pages; 22 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 2a)
    Includes cast listing; a synopsis of scenery designed by W. Telbin, J. Harker, and Hawes Craven; and a list of other productions in July.
    Tennyson, Alfred Baron, 1809-1892. Becket; Theater programs; Terriss, William, d. 1897; Cattermole, Charles, active 1859; Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905
  - Becket: newspaper review of the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1893 February 7; 1 page (2 clippings); 56 x 13 cm (each 28 x 13 cm) (Box 1, Folder 2b)
    The name of the newspaper is unidentified, but includes the word "Morning" in its title. The clipping includes illustrations by Charles Cattermole.
    Tennyson, Alfred Baron, 1809-1892. Becket; Clippings; Costume design drawings; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); Cattermole, Charles, active 1859; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Ward, Genevieve, 1838-1922; Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1847-1928; Terriss, William, d. 1897
  - Becket: newspaper advertisement for the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1893; 1 page (2 clippings); 58 x 14 cm (each 29 x 14 cm) (Box 1, Folder 2c)
    Includes advertisements for opera at Covent Garden Theatre, announcements and exhibitions at various theatres, including Theatre Royal at Drury Lane, Haymarket Theatre, Strand Theatre, Crystal Palace Pantomime, Trafalgar Square Theatre, Empire Theatre, and Palace Theatre.
    Tennyson, Alfred Baron, 1809-1892. Becket; Clippings; Advertisements; Cattermole, Charles, active 1859; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Ward, Genevieve, 1838-1922; Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1847-1928; Terriss, William, d. 1897
  - Charles I: program for the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1893 June 28; 4 pages; 22 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 3a)
    Includes advertisements for upcoming productions, including The Lyon's Mail, The Merchant of Venice, Olivia, Much Ado About Nothing, Becket, King Henry VIII, Nance Oldfield and The Bells.
    Wills, W. G. (William Gorman), 1828-1891. Charles I; Theater programs; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912; Terriss, William, d. 1897
  - Cymbeline: program for the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1896 December 9; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); 4 pages; 21.5 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 4a)
    Includes cast listing, as well as advertisements for The Bells, The King and the Miller, and Richard III.
    Theater programs; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905
  - Faust: program for the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1886 January 23; 4 pages; 21.5 x 16 cm (Box 1, Folder 5a)
    Includes a cast listing and a synopsis of the scenery.
    Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Faust; Theater programs; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Wills, W. G. (William Gorman), 1828-1891; Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1847-1928; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905
  - Find the Woman: program for the London Coliseum production, 1914 May 4; 12 pages; 21.5 x 14 cm (Box 1, Folder 6a)
    Includes 10 acts of various types (vaudeville, ballet, short plays, etc.) culminating in Arthur Bourchier and Garrick Theatre Company's presentation of the third act of Charles Klein's Find the Woman.
    Advertisements; Theater programs; London Coliseum (London, England); Klein, Charles, 1867-1915; Vanbrugh, Violet, 1867-1942; Bourchier, Arthur, 1863-1927
  - Find the Woman: insert for the London Coliseum production, 1914 May; 4 pages; 19 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 6b)
    Includes a synopsis of the first two acts of the play.
    Advertisements; Theater programs; Vanbrugh, Violet, 1867-1942; Klein, Charles, 1867-1915; Bourchier, Arthur, 1863-1927
  - Henry IV: program for the Theatre Royal Haymarket production, 1896 July 2; Haymarket Theatre (London, England); 4 pages; 16.5 x 18 cm (Box 1, Folder 7a)
    Program for Part I, produced by Herbert Beerbohm Tree, who also played Sir John Falstaff. Directed by Tree and Louis Calvert. Includes advertisements.
    Theater programs; Advertisements; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Calvert, Louis, 1859-1923; Haymarket Theatre (London, England); Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, Sir, 1852-1917
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream: program for the Globe Theatre production, 1890 January 15; 4 pages; 25.5 x 19 cm (Box 1, Folder 8a)
    An F.R. Benson production. Includes a cast listing, a list of scenes and music, and an advertisement for other plays.
    Globe Theatre (London, England: 1599-1644); Theater programs; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Midsummer night's dream; Benson, Frank R. (Frank Robert), 1858-1939
  - Richard III: program for the Royal Lyceum Theatre production, 1897 April 6; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); 4 pages; 21.5 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 9a)
    Starring Henry Irving as Richard. Bram Stoker is listed as the Acting Manager. Includes advertisement for Sardou's Madame Sans-Gene with Ellen Terry in the starring role and Henry Irving playing Napoleon.
    Theater programs; Terry, Ellen, Dame, 1847-1928; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912; Lyceum Theatre (London, England)
  - The Scarlet Pimpernel: playbill for the Borough Theatre production, 1903 April; 6 pages (1 folded sheet); 25.5 x 37.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 10a)
    Produced at the Borough Theatre and Opera House, Stratford, by Fred Terry. Includes advertisements.
    Advertisements; Theater programs; Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness, 1865-1947; Terry, Fred, 1863-1933
  - Twelfth Night: program for the Old Vic production, 1924 May; Old Vic Company; 4 pages; 19 x 12.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 11a)
    Program for the final production of the 1923-1924 season. Includes advertisements for two operas, The Marriage of Figaro and Don Giovanni.
    Theater programs; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Baylis, Lilian, 1874-1937; Old Vic Theatre (London, England)
  - The Two Gentlemen of Verona: playbill for the Daly's Theatre production, 1895 July 5; Daly's Theatre (London, England); 4 pages; 18 x 27 cm (Box 1, Folder 12a)
    Program for Augustin Daly's Company of Comedians' fourth production of The Two Gentlemen of Verona. Includes announcements for additional performances and the company's first production of Midsummer Night's Dream as well as presentations of Nancy & Co., The Honeymoon and The Heart of Ruby.
    Advertisements; Theater programs; Rehan, Ada, 1857-1916; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Daly, Augustin, 1838-1899; Power, Tyrone, 1869-1931; Daly's Theatre (London, England)
  - Multiple Productions: press release for the National Standard Theatre announcing the first London appearance of Edmund Tearle and his company, 1887 April 18; Standard Theatre (Shoreditch, London, England); 4 pages (1 folded sheet); 19 x 13 cm (Box 1, Folder 13a)
    During the week of April 8th, 1887, Tearles and company performed Sheridan Knowles' Virginius, Shakespeare's Hamlet and Richard III, and the farce His Last Legs. Included in the press release are advertisements for the Olympic Theatre production of A Dark Secret.
    Advertisements; Standard Theatre (Shoreditch, London, England); Tearle, Edmund, 1856-1913
  - Multiple Productions: program for the Palace Theatre of London of Varieties, 1908 June 27; Palace Theatre (London, England); 1 page (folded); 29 x 41 cm (Box 1, Folder 13b)
    Included in the program are performances by American vaudeville star Walter C. Kelly. The program also mentions Florence Yaymen, a "Coon Caricaturist." Advertisements also included.
    Advertisements; Theater programs; Kelly, Walter C., 1873-1939; Palace Theatre (London, England); Allan, Maud
  - Multiple Productions: program for the Royal Lyceum Theatre's "Last Night of the Season", 1896 July 25; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); 4 pages; 21.5 x 17 cm (Box 1, Folder 13c)
    Includes cast listings for Romeo and Juliet, For the Crown, Magda, King Henry VIII, and The School for Scandal.
    Theater programs; Lyceum Theatre (London, England); Irving, Henry, Sir, 1838-1905; Forbes-Robertson, Johnston, Sir, 1853-1937; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Harrison, Frederick, 1853 or 1854-1926
  - Obituary of Adelaide Ristori from The Morning Post, 1906 October 10; 1 obituary in 2 clippings; 30 x 7 and 11 x 7 cm (Box 1, Folder 14a)
    Obituary of the Italian actress. Her famous roles include Lady Macbeth, Phaedra, Medea, Queen Elizabeth, Deborah, Judith, and Camilla.
    Clippings; Ristori, Adelaide, 1822-1906
- Designs by Production, Series II; Hockley, Edgar, 1860-1938
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawing of three figures, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 18 x 23 cm (Box 2, Folder 1a)
    The watercolor (6 x 7 cm) is affixed to the larger sheet, which includes detailed description of the coloring of the figures and their costumes.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Watercolors; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawing of Cleopatra standing in front of her throne, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 19 x 12 cm (Box 2, Folder 1b)
    "Magenta" written on the middle to lower left corner.
    Watercolors; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawing of Cleopatra with two of her serving women, Charmian and Iras, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 10 x 12 cm (Box 2, Folder 1c)
    Includes notes on the color of the costumes.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Graphite drawings
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawings of various heads and torsos, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 1(d))
    Includes detailed sketches of three headdresses and annotations for the female figure.
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Graphite drawings
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawings of two rooms, in Egypt and Rome, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink and graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 1e)
    Folded sheet includes multiple drawings on both sides. Includes details of a pillar and vases or urns for the banquet to Antony, as well as a male headdress.
    Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Graphite drawings
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawing of Calpurnia, Caesar, and Antony, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 1(f))
    The watercolor (6.5 x 7 cm) is affixed to the larger sheet, which includes descriptions of the color and texture of the costumes.
    Watercolors; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Costume design drawings
  - Antony and Cleopatra: drawing of a woman on horseback, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 9.5 x 10 cm (Box 2, Folder 1g)
    The drawing presumably depicts Cleopatra.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Antony and Cleopatra; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - As You Like It: drawings of costume design for Orlando, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 2a)
    Includes notes on the color of the costume.
    Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. As you like it
  - As You Like It: drawing of costume design for a male, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: pen and ink; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 2b)
    Includes notes on the color and design of the costume.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. As you like it; Pen and ink drawings
  - As You Like It: drawings of costume design for a female with legging detail, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 2c)
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. As you like it
  - Charles I: drawing of a male on throne, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 3a)
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Wills, W. G. (William Gorman), 1828-1891. Charles I
  - Charles I: drawing of a room at Hampton Court, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 3b)
    The reverse side includes the notation "Hampton Court" in the upper left corner.
    Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Wills, W. G. (William Gorman), 1828-1891. Charles I; Hampton Court (Richmond upon Thames, London, England)
  - Charles I: drawing of a boat, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 3c)
    The small sheet includes a sketch of a gondola-like boat, with passengers, on a canal. A second sheet (18 x 22.5 cm), once presumably used to protect the first, contains the notation, "Charles 1st (H.B. Irving)."
    Wills, W. G. (William Gorman), 1828-1891. Charles I; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings; Graphite drawings
  - Charles I: drawing of a male genuflecting, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 11.5 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 3(d))
    The sketch includes a male genuflecting before another male (presumably Charles I), while in the background a female looks on.
    Wills, W. G. (William Gorman), 1828-1891. Charles I; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings; Set design drawings
  - Coriolanus: drawings of Aufidius and Lieutenant watching procession and tents, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 19 x 14 cm (Box 2, Folder 4a)
    Includes notes on the colors of a temple, a vase, tents, cloaks, helmets, the ground, and symbols.
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Coriolanus; Graphite drawings
  - Coriolanus: drawing of a fortress and soldiers in the woods, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 19 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 4b)
    Includes notes on the colors of flora, a fortress, and soldiers.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Coriolanus; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Cymbeline: drawing of a cave in mountains, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 5a)
    Sketch, 7.5 x 17 cm, appears on the top half of the page, and presumably depicts the cave of Belarius.
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Graphite drawings
  - Cymbeline: drawing of Pisanio and Imogen, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 5b)
    Includes color notes for Pisanio and Imogen's costumes.
    Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Cymbeline: drawings of four males and Imogen's bedchamber, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 5c)
    Includes color and detail notes for costumes and a bedchamber set.
    Set design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Graphite drawings; Costume design drawings
  - Cymbeline: drawing of soldiers marching, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 9.5 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 5(d))
  - Cymbeline: drawings of a male costume, shields, and a chariot, circa 1886-1897; 6 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 5e)
    Includes color notes and details for a male tunic and cloak, two types of shields, as well as a horse and chariot.
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Graphite drawings; Set design drawings
  - Cymbeline: unidentified photocopied reproduction of a painting of a soldier, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: photocopy; 12 x 6.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 6a)
    Set design drawings; Costume design drawings; Photocopies; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline
  - Cymbeline: drawing of Imogen in male costume, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 6b)
    Costume design drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Graphite drawings
  - Cymbeline: drawings of Imogen in various poses, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: pen and ink and graphite; 20 x 13 cm (Box 2, Folder 6c)
    Depicts a female in male costume, presumably Imogen. Includes color notes for the costume and a staff.
    Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline
  - Cymbeline: drawing of Imogen in male costume, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 6(d))
    Costume design drawings; Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline
  - Cymbeline: drawings of Imogen, in three poses, in male costume, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 11 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 6e)
  - Cymbeline: drawing of Imogen in male costume, holding a document, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings: graphite; 18 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 6(f))
    The verso contains color and detail notes on the costume and actress' hair, as well as a small drawing depicting cuff details, etc.
  - Cymbeline: drawings of three males, circa 1886-1897; 4 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 23.5 x 19 cm (Box 2, Folder 6g)
    Includes color and detail notes on the costumes.
    Graphite drawings; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. Cymbeline; Costume design drawings
  - Cymbeline: drawing of Imogen, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: graphite; 17 x 11 cm (Box 2, Folder 6h)
    Includes detail notes on the costume as well as what may be lighting direction.
  - Cymbeline: drawings of Caius Lucius and Posthumus Leonatus, circa 1886-1897; 3 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 6i)
    Includes color and detail notes on the costumes, as well as a back view of Posthumus Leonatus.
  - Cymbeline: drawings of four males and a sleeping figure, circa 1886-1897; 5 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 6j)
    Includes color and detail notes on the costumes and hair.
  - Davy Garrick: drawing of a male with his right hand aloft, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor and gouache over graphite and pen and ink; 17.5 x 11.5 cm (Box 2, Folder 6.1a)
    The drawing (6 x 4 cm) is affixed to the larger sheet, which includes detail and color notes for the costume.
    Costume design drawings; Pen and ink drawings; Graphite drawings; Gouaches; Watercolors; Robertson, T. W. (Thomas William), 1829-1871; Garrick, David, 1717-1779
  - Don Juan: drawing of Don Juan d'Autriche, circa 1886-1897; 1 drawing: watercolor over graphite; 16 x 9 cm (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Includes the following text: "Don Juan d'Autriche -- Theatre Francais, 6 Fev' 1836." Delavigne's play debuted in 1835.
    Graphite drawings; Delavigne, Casimir, 1793-1843. Don Juan d'Autriche; Watercolors; Costume design drawings
  - Faust: drawings of a female costume, circa 1886-1897; 2 drawings on 1 sheet: graphite; 13 x 20 cm (Box 2, Folder 8a)